Cray Smith

Longmont, CO | Phone: 970-978-2971 | Email: cmsmith004@gmail.com

GitHub: https://github.com/SmithCray

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/cray-smith-bb175b223/

OBJECTIVE

Hi my name is Cray Smith! I'm currently a student at DU under the Full-Stack Flex program. I'm excited to learn all I can and create something new and exciting! Moving forward my goal is to establish a position in Coding and Development as well as push myself to learn new and challenging technologies. As a Junior Developer I want to gain reliable real-world experience in a challenging and thriving environment while building on the tools and techniques I've learned so far. Career and Team driven attitude, with a friendly and helpful personality.

TECHNOLOGY

Web Development and Coding:

- HTML
- Advanced-CSS
- JavaScript
- Web API's
- Node JS
- Express
- SQL
- NoSQL
- Mongo DB
- <u>Computer Science</u>
- Zoom/ Remote experience

SKILLS & ABILITIES

Sales:

- Familiar with customer sales
- Prior sales experience
- Point of sale (POS) and register experience
- <u>Customer product ordering experience</u>

Communication:

- Customer service experience
- <u>Customer care experience</u>
- Great communication skills

SKILLS:

- Forklift operation 8+ years
- "Order picker" (standing lift platform)
- Heavy equipment
- <u>Trailer pulling experience 12ft 26ft</u>
- Pallet jack
- Backhoe operation
- Street sweeper
- Skid loader
- **Bobcat operation**
- Extensive equipment operation experience
- Tools and equipment

Leadership:

- Leadership skills and experience
- Team operations experience
- Teamwork skills
- Ability to lead

EXPERIENCE

Current:

Student at University of Denver

CURRENT-

Study: Web Development and Coding

Full Stack Flex Program- Web/Junior Development

Builders First Source - LONGMONT, CO

AUG 2018- JUNE 2021

- YARD FOREMAN/ LOADBUILDER
- Manage and supervise on site operations and personnel
- Assist in Team Building and interview process

Large scale construction supply

- Run daily safety and production focused "Quick start" meetings
- **Customer Service**
- Build custom orders
- Product knowledge
- Product care
- Product accuracy
- Attention to detail

TZ Designz - Pahoa HI (Contracted employment). PROJECT TEAM LEAD/ SALES/ ADVERTISEMENT

JUNE 2017- MARCH 2018

- Small business starter employee and team lead
- Production of product (custom designed apparel)
- Market setup and operations
- Sales and inventory management
- Design and print custom apparel
- Resource and communicate with local artists and small businesses
- Advertisement (company and designs)
- Custom orders

Contact number: (808) 426-6053 Supervisor: Zach Hahn

THE HOME DEPOT - GREELEY, CO. SHIPPING SPECIALIST/ SALES ASSOCIATE

OCT 2014- JUNE 2017

- Shipping duties included receiving and shipping store inventory, detailing and receiving customer PO's, Heavy equipment operation (Standing "slip truck" fork lift, sit down heavy propane powered lift, and "order picker" standing lift platform)
- Order puller duties included product gathering for various orders and time sensitive deadlines.
- Delivery truck load and unload, and product
- <u>Help customers find products</u>
- Responsible for general store cleanliness, presentation, and safety.
- Quality control
- Responsible for customer and client safety

Contact number: (970) 506-0662 Supervisor: Robyn DeMeyer (HR)

Devoe Contracting - KERSEY, CO.

JUNE 2014- Sept 2014

ROUSTA-BOUT

- Oil field maintenance, and construction
- <u>Heavy equipment operation (Street sweeper, backhoe, forklift, skid loader, jumping jack, and</u> small equipment)
- Hard labor responsibilities
- Travel and transport of equipment and crew
- Responsible for equipment maintenance
- Item inquiry and organization
- Shift and day's work records

Contact number: (970) 284-7824 Supervisor: Shawn Devoe

Walmart Distribution Center - WINDSOR, CO. SHIPPING/ ORDERFILLING

May 2012- JUNE 2013

- Forklift operator
- Shipping and receiving associate
- Package handling and care/ product insurance
- Fill existing orders with in stock merchandise
- Package, label, and ship product
- Load trailers/ palletize product
- Unload/ load pallet trailers (Forklift)
- Team oriented goals, general safety assurance, and time management development.

Contact number: (970) 663-7870 Supervisor: N/A

KOHL'S Department Store - GREELEY, CO.

MARCH 2010- APRIL 2014

backroom associate/ Sales BACKROOM ASSOCIATE/ SALES

- Operations lead
- Dock and backroom responsibility
- Unload/ load trailers
- Product insurance
- Return damaged products to company distribution
- Pallet jack and shipping operations experience.
- Backroom/ dock merchandise handling and store merchandise as well as back stock overflow control
- <u>Price change team member responsibilities included sensitive information handling (Upcoming</u> sales, items included in special events including Black Friday, and next day deals)

Contact number: (970) 330-0489 Supervisor: Jeanette Chinn-Polzin

SEVEN ELEVEN – GREELEY, CO.

MARCH 2013- JUNE 2013

SALES ASSOCIATE

- Point of sale associate, sales and customer care responsibilities
- Product ordering and stocking
- Assist in product unload
- On shelf order fulfillment
- Cleaning and store maintenance
- Gas and propane safety and use procedures

Contact number: (970) 353-0077 Supervisor: Jenn Fisher

Liberty Tax – GREELEY, CO.

JAN 2011- APRIL 2011

ADVERTISEMENT (contracted employment)

- <u>Business to business advertisement</u>
- <u>Customer relations and service, and communication skills</u>
- Short term employment during tax season

Contact number: (970) 356-6495 Supervisor: N/A

EDUCATION

High School Diploma | 2010 | Weld County High School:

General Education, K-12

Associate of Arts | Aims Community Collage

• <u>Associate of Arts program incomplete</u>

Full Stack Flex Program | 2021 | University of Denver (Web Development/ Coding)

- <u>Full Stack Flex, Full-Time Online</u>
- Web/Junior Development

CERTIFICATIONS

- Defensive Driving, Expiration date 07/26/2015
- Loader/Backhoe Operator and Safety Training, Expiration date 07/19/2017
- PEC Safety (Safe Land).
- Encana Safety, Expiration date 07/2015